Guide to the Lesly Lempert Collection, 1987-1994.
Lempert, Lesly Collection
- Series I. Periodicals
  - Statement by National Figures from Occupied Palestine, August 15, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 531)
    Producer: [National Figures from Occupied Palestine]
  - Percecption of Legal Inequality in Deeply Divided Societies: The Case of Israel, [July 10-12, 1991] (Box 9, Folder 532)
  - Victims of the Intifadah: Statistical Profile, August, 1989; draft (Box 9, Folder 533)
    Producer: Elia Zureik, Queen's University
  - Israel's Use of Extrajudicial Killings in the Occupied Territories, [April 29, 1992]; transmittal (Box 9, Folder 533)
  - Crime, Justice, and Underdevelopment: The Palestinians Under Israeli Control, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 534)
  - Women and the Politics of Religion in Israel, November, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 535)
    Producer: Philippa Strum, Human Rights Quarterly
    Volume/Number: 11.4
  - The Power of the Religious Right in Israel: Origins and Growth. (Box 9, Folder 535)
    Producer: Philippa Strum
  - Resolutions and Policy Positions of the National Lawyers Guild Concerning the Middle East, Summer 1989 (Box 9, Folder 536)
    Producer: Middle East Subcommittee of the International Committee of the National Lawyer's Guild
  - The Hell: Palestinian Prisoners in Israeli Jails, [1989?] (Box 9, Folder 537)
    Producer: Ghassan Abdallah, Hettin Cultural Establishment
  - Can the Palestine Problem Be Solved?: Israeli Positions, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 538)
    Producer: Alouph Hareven (Editor), The Van Leer Jerusalem Foundation
  - Freedom of Speech: An American Perspective on the Israeli Dilema: The Keating Memorial Lecture, 1989--1990 (Box 9, Folder 539)
    Producer: Richard Polenberg, Tel Aviv University
  - [The Costs of Occupation: Deomcracy, Civil Liberties, and Human Rights in Intifada], [?]; Lecture outline and detailed lecture notes (Box 9, Folder 540)
    Producer: [Lesley Lempert?]
  - Query to Colleagues: This time around, is Middle East Watch going to condemn the curfew as collective punishment?, February 25, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 541)
    Producer: Gini Sherry (T/C Sa'eb Erekat)
  - Breaking the Siege: Israel's War Response: Every Home a Prison, February-March 1991; Newsletter (Box 9, Folder 542)
    Producer: Middle East Justice Network
    Volume/Number: 2.6
  - Different Scales of Justice: Arabs and Jews in Israel Results of National Survey (Occasional Paper), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 543)
    Producer: Near East Cultural and Educational Foundation of Canada, International Center for Research and Public Policy, U.S.A.
  - The Negev Bedouin Palestinian-Arab Population in Israel (Box 9, Folder 544)
    Producer: Association for Support and Defence of Bedouin Rights in Israel
  - A May 1st Gift--10 More Bedouin Houses Destroyed, May 9 1988 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - The Destruction of Olive Trees, Crops and Homes in Laqiya, May 8 1990 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Bedouin Village of Tarabin A-Son'a is Fenced Off, June 26 1990 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - The Bedouin Arabs of the Negev: the Struggle for Equal Rights as Citizens of Israel (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - (Correspondence) and Summary of the master Plan for the Bedouin Population in the Southern District (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - The EEC Ambassador Visits the Bedouin Arabs of the Negev (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Current Activities and News, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Attention: Medical Alert, Ferbuary 7, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 544)
    Producer: Association for Support & Defence of Bedouin Rights in Israel
  - Bedouin Arab Rights Report, November 1991-January 1992 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Bedouin Arab Rights Report, February-August 1992 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Bedouin Arab Rights Report, September-December 1992 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Bedouin Arab Rights Report, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Bedouins in the Negev: Attitudes and Aspirations Final Report, Apr-92 (Box 9, Folder 544)
    Producer: Massoud Eghbarieh, Muhammad Mahajneh, Association for Support & Defence of Bedouin Rights in Israel
  - Bi-Monthly Report, September 1990-October 1991 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Palestinian Bedouins 50 Years After the Nakbeh, [?] (Box 9, Folder 545)
  - How Israel Controls the Bedouin (Box 9, Folder 545)
    Producer: Ghazi Falah, Journal of Palestinian Studies
  - The Negev Bedouin: Key Statistics from the 1983 Census (Box 9, Folder 545)
    Producer: Benedict Roth, Shatil
  - Education Development Among Bedouin Tribes of the Negev (Box 9, Folder 545)
    Producer: Aref Abu-Rabia
  - Bedouin Arab Education in the Negev: Future Goals and Objectives, February 18 1990 (Box 9, Folder 545)
    Producer: Ismael Abu Saad
  - (Article): Beduin's Bloodt Code of Honour, November 20 1987 (Box 9, Folder 545)
  - Government Officials Uproot Beduin Olive Grove, October 29 1987 (Box 9, Folder 545)
    Producer: Elaine Ruth Fletcher, The Jerusalem Post
  - Beduin in the Negev Before 1948 (Box 9, Folder 545)
  - Changes in Bedouin Population (Box 9, Folder 545)
  - (Article): Unsafe Schools Keep Beduin Pupils at Home, February 6 1991 (Box 9, Folder 545)
  - Bedouins Banished, Ancient Jordan Caves Now Lose Tourism (Box 9, Folder 545)
    Producer: Judith Miller
  - Book List, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 546)
    Producer: Water Reports
  - Steering Committee and Board of Directors List (Box 9, Folder 548)
    Producer: Rabbis for Human Rights
  - Rabbis For Human Rights (Box 9, Folder 548)
  - Project Proposal: Advertising for Human Rights: Pilot Message (Box 9, Folder 548)
  - Basic Operating Budget, January 1-December 31 1991 (Box 9, Folder 548)
  - American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, Inc. project forms (Box 9, Folder 548)
  - Selected Press Clippings, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 549)
  - Giving Judaism Another Face, January, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 549)
  - Expropriation of Arab Lands for Soviet Jews?, September, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 549)
  - Joint RHR-Christian-Moslem Petition Brings Landmark High Court Ruling., July, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 549)
    Volume/Number: 2.3
  - Human Rights Study Guide (Box 9, Folder 549)
  - Project Proposal: Religious-Action Center (Box 9, Folder 550)
    Producer: Rabbinic Human Rights Watch
  - American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, Inc. Applications (Box 9, Folder 550)
  - Miscellaneous Rabbinic Documents (Box 9, Folder 551)
  - (Article): Non-Orthodox Candidates are Rejected by City Council, July 28 1989 (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Liat Collins, In Jerusalem
  - (Article): Rabbis and the Religious Council (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Rabbi Ehud Bandel
  - (Photograph) (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Isaac Harari, Press Photographer
  - (Article): Film Explores Both Sides of Complicated Israeli Conflict (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Michele Landsberg
  - (Article): Bearing Witness to Injustices, Winter 1990 (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Patricia Golan, Women's League
  - Women's League for Conservative Judaism, Summer 1991 (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Women's League outlook
    Volume/Number: 61.4
  - (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Masorti Movement
  - Israeli Palestinian Clerics Join their Efforts to Achieve Religious Freedom in the Holy Land. (Box 9, Folder 551)
  - Senior Price List, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Photoworks
  - National Board of Directors (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: US Interreligious Committee For Peace in the Middle East
  - May 6 1988 (Box 9, Folder 551)
  - Jewish Americans for Palestinian Self-Determination (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: American-Israelli Civil Liberties Coalition Inc.
  - (Article): Signers of Ad on Arab-Israeli Conflict Report Phone Threats (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Dennis Hevesi
  - Breaking the Silence, with Philippa Strum (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Voices from America
  - Civil Libertarian Says Israel Violates Some Rights, May,1988 (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Jewish Review
  - Occupation Corrupts Israeli Justice (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Boaz Evrom
  - Politics of Israel Assignment and Map, Spring 1988 (Box 9, Folder 552)
    Producer: Strum, Brooklyn College Department of Political Science
  - History: The Palestinian Arab Perspective (Box 9, Folder 552)
    Producer:Politics of Israel Course Material
  - Introduction and History (Box 9, Folder 552)
  - People of Israel (Box 9, Folder 552)
    Producer: Grose Ch. 3, Politics of Israel Course Material
  - Political Parties and Elections (Box 9, Folder 552)
    Producer: Arian, Politics of Israel Course Material
  - Occupation, Colonization, Apartheid: Defining the Conflict, Spring, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 554)
    Producer: Al Majdal
    Volume/Number: 33
  - Nakba Education on the Path of Return, Autumn, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 554)
    Volume/Number: 42
  - 60 Years on Honoring the Struggle for Justice and Dignity: Palestinian Refugees and IDPs (Box 9, Folder 554)
    Volume/Number: 36/37
  - Overcoming the Ongoing Nakba: BDS & the Global Anti-Apartheid Movement, Summer, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 555)
    Volume/Number: 38
  - Litigating Palestine: Holding Israel Accountable in the Courtroom, Spring/Summer, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 555)
    Volume/Number: 41
  - Forced Secondary Displacement: Palestinian Refugees in Arab Host Countries, Summer/Autumn 2010 (Box 9, Folder 555)
    Volume/Number: 44
  - Un-Greening the Third World: Food, Ecology and Power, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 556)
    Producer: Race and Class
  - A Study of Women and Work in 'Shatti' Refugee Camp of the Gaza Strip (Box 9, Folder 557)
    Producer: Erica Lang, Itimad Mohanna, Arab Thought Forum
  - Perpetual Limbo: Israel's Freeze on Unification of Palestinian Families in the Occupied Territories, July, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 557)
  - To Go to Berbir: A Journey and a War, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 558)
    Producer: Jill drew, Sinister Wisdom
    Volume/Number: 26
  - Conference: Human Rights and Peace in the Middle East, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 559)
    Producer: Syracuse Journal of International Law and Commerce
    Volume/Number: 13.3
  - Zemi Blum (Box 9, Folder 560)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings (Box 9, Folder 561)
  - Dr. Mamdouh Aker Arrest, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 562)
  - Dr. Riad Malki (Box 9, Folder 563)
  - Miscellaneous Documents pertaining to Palestinian Curfews, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 564)
  - New York Times Clippings, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 565)
  - (Article): Military Censorship Rules, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 566)
  - IDF Says it Arrested 350 Hamas Activists (Box 9, Folder 567)
    Producer: Mideast Mirror
  - Curfew in Territories being lifted in Stages (Box 9, Folder 567)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from The Abraham Fund], November 7, 1990--December 6, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 485)
    Producer: Abraham Fund, American-ISraeli Civil Liberties Coalition
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1982--1991 (Box 8, Folder 486)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1991--1994 (Box 8, Folder 487)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition regarding Contributions and Funding], April 26, 1983--March 1, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 488)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition regarding Fundraising Letters], December 1, 1982--June 8, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 489)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition regarding New Membership], 1987--1988 (Box 9, Folder 490)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition regarding fundraising], 1989--1990 (Box 9, Folder 491)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1982--1984 (Box 9, Folder 492)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1988--1989 (Box 9, Folder 493)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1988--1989 (Box 9, Folder 494)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1989--1990 (Box 9, Folder 495)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition regarding taxes], 1988--1990 (Box 9, Folder 496)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1989--1990 (Box 9, Folder 497)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, particularly regarding finances], 1987--1994 (Box 9, Folder 498)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1989--1990 (Box 9, Folder 499)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition], 1988--1990 (Box 9, Folder 500)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Amnesty International], 1988--1991 (Box 9, Folder 501)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Arab Association for Human Rights], January 31, 1994--April 13, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 502)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Aseel Research and Information], March 8, 1991--March 10, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 503)
    Producer: Aseel Research and Information
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the Association of Israeli-Palestinian Physicians for Human Rights], May 20, 1991--January 21, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 504)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from B'Tselem, November, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 505)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Beth Goldring], June 6, 1991--July 10, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 506)
    Producer: Beth Goldring, Lesley I. Lempert
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Cornell Civil Liberties Coalition], April 3, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 507)
    Producer: Cornell Civil Liberties Coalition
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Episcopal Church in Jerusalem and the Middle East], March 10, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 508)
    Producer: Episcopal Church in Jerusalem and the Middle East
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Gaza Center for Rights and Law], June 5, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 509)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Gaza Center for Rights and Law regarding a request for funding], 1990 -- 1991 (Box 9, Folder 510)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Al-Haq], November 25, 1986--October 18, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 511)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Human Rights Watch], August 2, 1989--December 29, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 512)
    Producer: Human Rights Watch, American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the International Center for Peace in the Middle East], October 17, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 513)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the International Jewish Peace Union], September, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 514)
    Producer: International Jewish Peace Union
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Israel Defence Forces], July 3, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 515)
    Producer: Israel Defence Forces
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from The Jerusalem Report], February 10, 1992--February 11, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 516)
    Producer: Jerusalem Report, American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Lea Tsemel], August 25, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 517)
    Producer: Lea Tsemel
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from the Middle East Chidren's Alliance], October 12, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 518)
    Producer: Middle East Children's Alliance
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Middle East Crisis Committee, February 12, 1990--March 3, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 519)
    Producer: Middle East Crisis Committee
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Middle East Policy Council], June 30, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 520)
    Producer: Middle East Policy Council
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Middle East Watch], June 19, 1991--February 17, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 521)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from New York Civil Liberties Union], July 22, 1992--July 26, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 522)
    Producer: New York Civil Liberties Union (NYCLU)
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Paul N. McCloskey, Jr.], January 16, 1985--April 21, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 523)
    Producer: Paul N. McCloskey, Jr., Carl Landman, Co., American Civil Liberties Coalition
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from Peter W. Nathanielsz, M.D., Ph.D.], June 9, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 524)
    Producer: Peter W. Nathanielsz, M.D., Ph.D.
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from State of Israel Ministry of Education], September 14, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 525)
    Producer: State of Israel Ministry of Education, Lesley I. Lempert
  - [Miscellaneous correspondence from The State of Israel Ministry of Justice], March 8, 1991--March 10, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 526)
    Producer: State of Israel Ministry of Justice, Middle East Watch
  - Re: The New Israeli High Court Agreement on Family Reunification, December 12, 1992; typescript (Box 9, Folder 527)
  - (Correspondence) and Summary of the master Plan for the Bedouin Population in the Southern District (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - (Correspondence to Friends and Supporters), July 10 1990 (Box 9, Folder 544)
    Producer: Nuri El-Okbi, Association for Support and Defence of Bedouin Rights in Israel
  - (Correspondence to Friends and Supporters), November 12 1990 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - (Correspondence to Friends and Supporters), February 26 1991 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - (Correspondence to Friends and Supporters), April 30 1991 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - (Various Correspondence Pertaining to Bedouins) (Box 9, Folder 545 A)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence from Rabbis for Human Rights, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 547)
  - (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1991 (Box 9, Folder 550)
  - (Miscellaneous Correspondence) (Box 9, Folder 551)
    Producer: Lesly Lempert
  - (Various Correspondence Pertaining to American-Israeli Civil Liberties Committee) (Box 9, Folder 553)